# **Abdullah**

Software Engineer

## Contact

**Address** 

Lahore, Pakistan, 90267

**Phone** 

923072777722

E-mail

aarainabdullah@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdullah-arain-7207452

# **Skills**

PHP development

Schema design

Agile Workflow

HTML

**CSS** 

**JavaScript** 

C++

Python

- Programming
- SQL platforms

Languages

C++ Programmer collaborates with multiple teams to accomplish various projects. Successfully developed custom solutions to solve challenges and engineered designs to meet predetermined functionality goals. Experience with, Object Oriented Programming and front-end also back-end Website Development solutions. Exceptional written and verbal communication skills as well as personal accountability.

# **Work History**

## 2022-04 -Current

## **PHP Web Developer**

Freelancer, lahore, pakistan

- Created web applications and components using PHP programming language.
- Managed user authentication and authorization for servers and various environments.
- Developed back-end components to connect applications with web services.
- Wrote server-side and client-side code for projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Created web applications and components using PHP programming language
- Wrote server-side and client-side code for projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript

#### 2022-02 -Current

# Full Stack Wordpress Web Developer

Freelancer, lahore, pakistan

- Created and updated re-usable code libraries to streamline WordPress development cycle.
- Leveraged strong understanding of WordPress core to manipulate admin and theme components.
- Implemented and assessed performance of SEO best practices.
- Referenced web analytics reporting to enhance designs and improve site performance.
- Designed responsive, mobile-first websites from design concepts.
- Teamed with design and project developers to understand project scope and offer elegant, creative and scalable solutions.
- Converted design assets into component-based



HTML, CSS and JavaScript

 Developed and implemented WordPress sites, themes and plugins

## 2020-01 -Current

#### C++ Language

Problem Solving, lahore, pakistan

- Relevant coursework: Object-oriented Programming,
  Data Structures and Algorithms, Database
  Development.
- Problem Solving Skills.
- Critical Thinking Skills.
- Flexibility.
- Communication Skills.
- Teamwork.
- Organization Skills.
- Creativity.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

## **Education**

2015-09 - A-Levels (CAIE): Engineering (Pre-Engineering)

Beaconhouse A-Levels Gulberg Campus -Lahore, pakistan

2020-01 -Current Bachelor of Software Engineering: Computer Engineering Technology

Univeristy of Central Punjab - Lahore, Pakistan

# **Hobbies**

Cricket makes me feel healthy, fit and a stronger person. It makes me feel confident and proud of what I am. I started playing cricket when I was a kid of 9 years old.